<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The 9th day of April. 1658. A true report of the great number of poor children, and other poor people maintained in the severall hospitals by the pious care of the Lord Mayor, Commonalty and citizens of the city of Lonson.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1658</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B06288</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T3094A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224222</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">51784686</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 51784686</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175086</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B06288)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175086)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2712:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The 9th day of April. 1658. A true report of the great number of poor children, and other poor people maintained in the severall hospitals by the pious care of the Lord Mayor, Commonalty and citizens of the city of Lonson.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1658]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Publication data suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Universität Göttingen Bibliothek.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Children --  Hospital care --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Poor --  Hospital care --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Soldiers --  Hospital care --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Hospital records --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-03</date>
            <label>Elspeth Healey</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Rekeyed and resubmitted</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="report">
            <pb facs="tcp:175086:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
            <head>
               <hi>The 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of</hi> April. 1658. A true Report of the great number of poor Children, and other poor people maintained in the ſeverall Hoſpitals by the pious care of the Lord Mayor, Commonalty and Citi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens of the City of LONDON.</head>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Hildren put forth Apprentices, &amp; diſcharged out of <hi>Chriſt Hoſpitall</hi> the yeare laſt paſt-101</item>
               <item>Children buried the ſaid year.—025</item>
               <item>Children now remaining under the care and Charge of the ſaid Hoſpitall which are kept in the houſe and divers places in <hi>London,</hi> and ſuburbs thereof, and at nurſe in the Countrey, One thouſand and two—1002</item>
               <item>The names of all which are Regiſtred in the Books kept in the ſaid Hoſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tall, and are there to be ſeen from what Pariſhes they have been from time to time admitted.</item>
               <item>The number being ſo many, and the charges of keeping of them ſo great, It is hoped ſeverall well affected perſons will freely Contribute towards the maintenance of them, the certain Revenew of the ſaid Hoſpitall being little more then the Moytie of the neceſſary Charges thereof.</item>
               <item>THere hath been Cured this yeare laſt paſt, at the Charge of S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. <hi>Bartholomews</hi> Hoſpitall, of mained Souldiers, Seamen and other diſeaſed perſons, many whereof being Souldiers and Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men have been relieved with money and other neceſſaries at their departure—1244</item>
               <item>Buried this year after much Charge in their ſickneſſe—0234</item>
               <item>Remaining under Cure at this preſent, at the charge of the ſaid Hoſpitall—286</item>
               <item>THere hath been Cured at the Charge of S<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. <hi>Thomas</hi> Hoſpitall, this year laſt paſt, of diſeaſed per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, whereof many being Souldiers and Seamen, have been relieved with money, and other neceſſaries at their departure—1085</item>
               <item>Buried this year after much Charge in the time of their ſickneſſe—217</item>
               <item>Remaining under Cure at preſent, upon the Charge of the ſaid Hoſpitall—256</item>
               <item>THere hath been brought to the Hoſpitall of <hi>Bridewell,</hi> within the ſpace of one whole year laſt paſt of wandring Souldiers, and other Vagrant people, to the number of—705</item>
               <item>Many whereof have been very chargeable to the ſaid Hoſpitall, for Apparell, ſick Dyet, and Surgery, beſides the ordinary dyet, and other proviſions and charges expended about them, which could not be avoided by reaſon of their neceſſities, and many of them have been paſſed into their native Countries, with Clothing, Apparell, and other charges, which could not be avoided, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidering their naked and miſerable condition, nor they thence paſſed without ſuch charge. And there are now kept and maintained in Arts and Occupations, and other uſefull and neceſſary works and labours, at the charge of the ſaid Hoſpitall, Apprentices and other perſons the number of—157</item>
            </list>
            <p>THe Hoſpitall of <hi>Bethlehem</hi> is of great Antiquity, uſe, and neceſſity, for keeping and curing diſtracted perſons, who are of all others moſt miſerable, by reaſon of their wants, both for ſoul and body, and have no ſenſe thereof.</p>
            <p>The charge thereof is very great, there being kept and maintained with Phyſick, Dyet, and other relief, 52 diſtracted perſons conſtantly at leaſt, beſides the charge of ſervants to look to them, they being moſt unruly and not able to help themſelves; and the Rents and Revenues of the ſaid Hoſpitall being very ſmall, not amounting to two third parts of the yearly charge, and therefore this Hoſpitall is a fit object of charity, there having been and daily are by the bleſſing of God, upon the charge of the ſaid Hoſpitall, and care of thoſe that are intruſted with the ſaid diſtracted people, divers reduced to their former ſenſes.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
